# Nitesh Karki

# **DevSecOps Engineer**

Mulpani-7, Kathmandu Nepal 44600 +9779843209020 nitacekarki@gmail.com

Linkedin: <a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/nitesh-karki-539832163/">https://www.linkedin.com/in/nitesh-karki-539832163/</a>

#### **SUMMARY**

An AWS certified Developer/SysOps engineer with 4+ years of experience in multi-national IT enterprise environments. Managed large scale servers, firewalls and networking, extremely proficient with cloud technology like AWS, VMware, Azure & Rackspace and have a deep passion for enterprise-wide system & security management.

#### **SKILLS**

- Deploy, manage, and operate scalable, highly available, and fault-tolerant systems on AWS/Microsoft Azure/Google Cloud/Digitalocean/Rackspace.
- Select the appropriate AWS service based on compute, data, or security requirements
- Identify appropriate use of AWS operational best practices
- Estimate AWS usage costs and identify operational cost control mechanisms with advanced cost optimization techniques
- Migrate on-premises workloads to Cloud
- Familiarity with operations of Python, Node.js, & php applications.
- Experience and knowledge of scripting with Bash & Python and IT Automation with Ansible.
- Experience with standing up a continuous delivery pipeline using tools like Jenkins, GitLabCl, Drone and Docker.
- Working knowledge on administering & deploying databases like
   PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB, MSSQL, DynamoDB & AWS Aurora.
- Experience on administering web & application servers like Apache,
   Nginx, Tomcat.
- Working knowledge of OAuth and LDAP integration and setup across custom apps.
- Experience and knowledge of Docker, Elastic Container Service & AWS EKS.
- Experience in automated Periodic Data backup & Disaster Recovery.
- Experience in IT infrastructure support (systems,Linux servers and firewall

- DNS | Nameservers | Domain Setup -- Management
- NagiosXI | zabbix | mon | ganglia -- monitoring and alerting system (both performance and alerting).
- Email Hosting and Manage | Webmail | Zimbra | Server domain email setup | GSuite | Zoho
- Management Tools | Trello | Red mine | Bug-Zilla | Atlassian Jira |
   Freshdesk
- Penetration testing | SQL injection | XSS

#### **EXPERIENCE**

## Tekkon Technologies - DevOps Engineer

November 2019 - Current, Baluwatar, Kathmandu

- Scalable Microservices architecture deployment and configuration
   Continuous Integration and Deployment for FrondEnd and Backend
   Stacks with tools like jenkins and GitlabCI.
- Customized and Integrated OpenSource tool that replaces functionalities of GSuite.
- Built secure and modern cloud infrastructure Architecture diagrams and implementation with CloudFormations following modern cloud guidelines.
- Build a solution to display logs from Cloudwatch using ElasticSearch and Kinesis Stream.
- Serverless Architecture using Lambda, Appsync, GraphQL and Cognito.
- Containerized deployments with advanced tools like EKS and ECS
- Monitoring and alerting system setup for large scale servers.

#### Genese Software Solution - Senior SysOps Engineer / IT Manager

Feb 2017 – October 2019, Maitidevi, Kathmandu

- Lead a support team of 20 System Engineers
- Deployment application and solutions for Top banks in nepal.
- Disaster Recovery team lead.
- Responsible for Managing All Nepal and UK clients for WebApp and Email hosting on Linux Server (CentOS & Ubuntu) (500+ Servers)
- Hired as a full-time systems administrator following an initial consulting
  role to manage and maintain a 50+ mixed server environment
  (Windows/Unix/Linux), ensuring 99.9% or better up time. Evaluate,
  monitor and enhance IT infrastructure with an emphasis on availability,
  reliability, scalability, security, data confidentiality and system integrity..

iFix Store - Associate Software Engineer

March 2016 - Jan 2017, Boudha, Kathmandu

 Worked in Apple Service Center: iFix Store Nepal as iPhone/iPad/Mac Software Troubleshooter and Technician.

## **EDUCATION**

## Nepal Engineering College / Bachelor in Computer Engineering

November 2013 - Jan 2018, Bhaktapur, Nepal

### Sagarmatha Multiple College / +2 Science

Year 2011 - Year 2013, Dillibazar, Kathmandu High School on Computer Science Faculty.

Score: 74.00%

#### Bal Geetanjali English School / SLC

Bhaktapur, Nepal Mulpani, Kathmandu Schooling from BGES

Score: 81.6%

#### **Skill Certifications**

- AWS Certified Developer Associate
- AWS Technical Professional
- AWS Business Professional
- AWS TCO & Cloud Economics
- AWS Professional EC2 Systems Manager
- Google Cloud Fundamentals- GSuite
- Google Adwords
- VMware Fundamentals
- Nagios Fundamentals
- Linux Ubuntu Member

# **Training**

- AWS SysOps Training Udemy & ACloud Guru
- AWS DevOps Training Udemy & ACloud Guru
- Nagios Training Online
- VMware Training
- GSuite Training
- Advance Linux Training Udemy & ACloud Guru

## **Projects**

- Data Visualization Project using Superset.
- Deployed and managed Nagios Monitoring tool to monitor the whole Nepal Router and Switches for the Largest Telecom in Nepal.
- Built custom Mass Emailing Solution that is able to send 1 lakh plus emails at once at very low cost (Used by 3 top Private Banks in Nepal)
- ERPNext -- Hosting, Optimizing, Customizing ERPNext Softwares.
- SysPass -- Hosting, Optimizing, Customizing SysPass for passwords and data encryption and Storing.
- Nagios -- Hosting in server, configuring hosts / websites /monitoring Linux/Windows Server.
- Sendy | TemplateBuilder -- Hosting, Customizing, Integrating with AWS SMTP
- eAttendance App -- used AWS Rekognition for image recognition and DynamoDB and S3 with Lambda for serverless computing.

## Reference

#### **Genese Software Solution**

Anjani Phuyal (Founder/Global CTO)

Relation: Direct Line Manager Contact: <a href="mailto:anjani@phuyal.co.uk">anjani@phuyal.co.uk</a>

Phone: +447412767100